<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>F1tZy</title>
    <link>http://f1tz81.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on F1tZy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 09:25:19 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://f1tz81.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Marketing to the Organization</title>
      <link>http://f1tz81.github.io/post/marketingtoorg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 09:25:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://f1tz81.github.io/post/marketingtoorg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my experience new ideas are not accepted within the organization when they are first uttered.
Even in a forward looking group like IT it can take time and effort for an idea to take hold. If you talk
to some they may say this is a political problem. I would look at this a slightly different way and pose this
as a marketing opportunity, that is right marketing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a day in age where outsourcing complicated work is an option and a time where other organizations can take
on your IT workload and do it for you, marketing is the key. Let me start with a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.oxforddictionaries.com/definition/marketing&#34;&gt;Definition From oxforddictionaries.com&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The action or business of promoting and selling products or services, including market research and advertising.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if marketing is the process of promoting / selling something can you see a place for it in an IT organization.
There is, every project / task / or activity you and your department do is either promoting or hurting the
image of your department within the organization. In order to gain control of that image and message we can
start using marketing practices and techniques. With increased awareness and recognition we can start to become
a trusted partner with in the organization instead of just the guys who take care of that technology stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have reached a place of trust and value you can start to get projects though, new ideas approved, and
make your department indispensable. How do we get there you ask, allow me to just give you a few ideas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell anyone that listen&lt;/strong&gt; - Simple awareness is one of the best tools you have. Tell every one you can about
the awesome things you group or department are doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Never miss an opportunity to answer to feedback&lt;/strong&gt; - Good or Bad feedback and how you and your group handle it
is important, always thanks someone for any feedback and truly listen and get a full understanding of what the
feedback is and there true motive for the feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Demos and Lunch &amp;amp; Learns&lt;/strong&gt; - Take every opportunity you can to show off what your group can do. Be excited
about it and show off the coolest things you can. This is another opportunity to cement expertise in the minds
of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Define a Goal and Unified Message&lt;/strong&gt; - In my experience this is one of the most awkward but crucial things to
do. Set a goal for the year / quarter / other length of time to achieve. Than great a message / slogan to help
communicate that goal. This will help give a better guideline for how to spread the word on what your group is
about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Examples:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    Spread Automation Testing across all digital products - Automate the Bits

    Migrate all mail accounts to Outlook - A better Message

    Go live in 3 new markets - Expanding Horizons
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make it as catchy as you can without stressing about it being perfect. It needs to communicate a message, not
win you awards.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The incorporation of Afterthought Games</title>
      <link>http://f1tz81.github.io/post/afterthoughtstart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:11:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://f1tz81.github.io/post/afterthoughtstart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://afterthoughtgames.com/assets/img/AfterthoughtLogoWhiteBlueBackground.png&#34; alt=&#34;Afterthought Logo&#34; height=&#34;350&#34; width=&#34;450&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AS of today all of the game projects that I have been working on at OST Games have now been incorporated
in to a new company called Afterthought Games. The projects include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cornflowercorbin.com&#34;&gt;Cornflower Corbin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://violentsol.com&#34;&gt;Violent Sol: Worlds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come check out the new website and get the low down on how things are moving on the projects on there
respective websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://f1tz81.github.io/image/14358883_1791480321092671_5720240604644609498_n.png&#34; alt=&#34;Grand Gamers Guild&#34; height=&#34;350&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other news Afterthought pickup on a new project. We are working with
&lt;a href=&#34;http://grandgamersguild.com/&#34;&gt;Grand Gamers Guild&lt;/a&gt; to bring both Stroop and Unreal Estate to a computer
and mobile phone near you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another Day Of Game Dev</title>
      <link>http://f1tz81.github.io/post/20160204/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 22:30:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://f1tz81.github.io/post/20160204/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a long day at my day job and some family time I started work on Violent Sol.
With our first internal release coming up it is important to get the finishing touches on
on what really is a robust system with a simple little game built in. The amount of interaction
really is just shooting bugs on a top down forest and picking health orbs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may seem like a small thing but most of our work for the past 3 months or so has been
on building the foundation for a truly epic game in scope. Here are our features so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Structure of the universe that can support planet play, space, and even other dimensions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stream loading content cache that should keep our game in a small memory foot print.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;100% modable Entity system that can load external DLL and configs to add to the game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rendering system that allows for thousands of entities on the screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple but extendable GUI system that allows for unlimited layered rendering and control input&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Client / Universe model that allows for easy network code in the near future&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple but flexible animation system based on simple sprite sheets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The start of a simple analytics engine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A failed Kickstarter campaign&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A successful Geenlit campaign&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Lot more that I am forgetting right now&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we are speeding along to what is one awesome engine and a simple game to release to
family, friends, and coworkers. It is worth every hour.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://f1tz81.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:35:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://f1tz81.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Welcome all to my little corner of the Internet. Since this is sort of my first official post let me give you the low down on who I am.
I am a father and software developer, in that order. My day job for the time being is both web development and automation. My
true passion in my software is Game Development. Now that we have the intro out of the way lets dive in to what I do where.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;web-development:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Web Development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My training and bulk of my experience has been in the world of Desktop Application(as in compiles a binary) and Systems Development.
In the last few years I have branched out in to Web Development. It has been fun and presents a whole new set of challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;automation:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Automation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you might have read that text above and wondered what I meant by automation. It is some what a vague term so allow me to explain.
What I mean by automation is using software to automate other software or business processes. The bulk of my work has been in the
application testing space. This is using sets of tools and custom code to test web sites or desktop applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;game-development:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Game Development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;O the mighty and awesome challenge of building virtual experiences. I have a love for creating entire worlds with in small digital devices. It
is the reason I started my track in to software development. My specialty is Game Architecture, but I love most jobs in this field. Just don&amp;rsquo;t
ask this poor coder to hand you art, your game characters will turn in to small squares.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that sums up my professional life. For the most part that is all this little blog will cover. There might be a few cameo posts about my thoughts
and feelings but this will not include family and friends. Check back often.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>http://f1tz81.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:02:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://f1tz81.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Here is a short list of my current projects around the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;game-dev:3c42bb4157bf51d85ae7ffc4e1685909&#34;&gt;Game Dev&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.violentsol.com/&#34;&gt;Violent Sol&lt;/a&gt; - An awesome top down survival game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ostgames.github.io/ludumdare34/&#34;&gt;Cornflower Corban&lt;/a&gt; - A side scrolling shoot&amp;rsquo;em up made for Ludumdare 34.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/F1tZ81/TiledMinkay&#34;&gt;TiledMinkay&lt;/a&gt; - Simple Library to load TMX files in DotNet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;automation:3c42bb4157bf51d85ae7ffc4e1685909&#34;&gt;Automation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/F1tZ81/Protractor-jvm&#34;&gt;Protractor JVM&lt;/a&gt; - A port of Protractor to the java virtual machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/F1tZ81/WebDriverExtended&#34;&gt;Webdriver Extneded&lt;/a&gt; - A set of small extensions for Selenium / Webdriver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;personal:3c42bb4157bf51d85ae7ffc4e1685909&#34;&gt;Personal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dungeonsandshotguns.org/&#34;&gt;Dungeons and Shotguns&lt;/a&gt; - A small family oriented gaming group. Includes a hosted Minecraft, Starbound, and various other game servers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>